绿 巨 人
绝没有办法能防御所有的战争生物制剂
There's simply no way to shield against every weaponized agent.
1966年 沙漠基地
但通过强化人体细胞的反应能力...
I nstead, I can make super-immune systems...
我能制造一个超级免疫系统
by strengthening the human cellular response.
斑纳 我知道你想说明什么
Banner, I know where you're going.
但操纵免疫系统这种事是非常危险和愚蠢的
But manipulating the immune system is dangerous and stupid.
总统的科学顾问已经说的很清楚了...
Thepresident's science advisors made it absolutely clear--
不能拿人来做实验
no human subjects.
大卫 我有个好消息
David, I have wonderful news.
我怀孕了
I 'm gonna have a baby.
是什么呢?布鲁斯 啊 想要那个恐龙吗?
What's it gonna be? Whoa, look at that, Bruce. Huh? Want a dinosaur?
来啊 让他们打一仗 来啊!
Let's have a little fight.
你吓不倒我
You don'tscare me.
那真是个好吃的眼珠 你又大又绿好吓人啊 我要逃了
That's a delicious eyeball. Ooh, you're big and green and scary. I'm gonna run away.
说真的 谈到查理...
Really, speaking ofCheryl, guess what--
布鲁斯 你受伤了
Bruce, you're hurt!
杰客用木棒打他 但布鲁斯不还手
Jack hit him with the stick, but Bruce wouldn't hit him back.
他只是站在那里发抖
He just stood there, shaking.
没事了
It's okay.
好奇怪 他一声也不吭
Yeah, strange he didn't make a peep.
要是别的孩子 可能已经哭得满地打滚了
Any other kid would've wailed his head off.
布鲁斯就是这样
That's Bruce. He's like that.
他...感情一向不外露
He's just so... bottled up.
我们在你实验室找到的样本...是人血
The samples we found in your lab--theywere human blood.
你无视我们的约定
You've ignored protocol.
你没权在我实验室里乱翻
You had no right snooping around in my lab.
这是我的事
That's my business.
错了 斑纳 这是政府的事 这项实验你被开除了
Wrong, Banner. It's government business, and you're offthe project.
全体人员注意 紧急程序已经启动
Attention, all personnel. Fail-safe has been initiated.
伽马射线污染会在30分钟后爆发
Gamma decontamination will occur in 30 minutes!
立即撤离
Evacuate immediately!
重复 立即撤离
I repeat, evacuate immediately!
- 伊迪丝?  - 大卫 怎么回事?
- Edith?   - David, what's going on?
- 我有话跟你说 伊迪丝  - 布鲁斯 待在这
- I gotta talk to  you, Edith.   - Bruce, stay here.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
What areyou doing?
我告诉你什么应该做!
I'm trying to tellyou what has to be done!
大卫 请停下 不
David, please stop it! No!
- 不要!不要!  - 要!
- No! No!   - Yes!
大卫 不要
David! No!
布鲁斯
Bruce.
布鲁斯 醒醒 孩子
Bruce, wake up, son.
布鲁斯
Bruce. Bruce.
又是个噩梦?
Another nightmare?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不记得了
I don't remember.
你好 妈妈
Hi, Mom.
你就要上大学了
Already off to college.
会想念你的
Gonna miss you terribly.
我也会想你的
I'll miss you too.
来 过来
Please, come here.
看看你
Look at  you.
马上就要成为一个伟大的科学家
Soon to be a great scientist.
我想是的
I guess.
- 谁知道呢?  - 我知道
- I mean, who knows?   - I do.
你有些地方...非常特别
There's something inside you... so special.
一些很伟大的地方
Some kind of greatness.
我肯定总有一天你会...
I'm sure somedayyou're gonna...
将这些与全世界分享
share it with the whole world.
柏克莱核生化学院
但我所关心的是 保安应该...
But as far as I'm concerned, security oughta be--
- 早安  - 早安 克伦斯勒博士
- Good morning.   - Good morning, Dr. Krenzler.
安全措施应该加强 这种地方 再小心也不过分
Security oughta be beefed up. In a place like this you can't be too careful.
布鲁斯 大日子
Bruce! Big day.
- 你睡的好吗?我没睡着  - 我睡得很好
- Did you sleep? I didn't sleep.   - I slept okay.
- 贝蒂在吗?  - 她就在附近
- Is Betty here?   - She's around.
我要说 看你那么时髦的头饰...
I really gotta say, seeing you in that stylin' head wear--
你是在暗指我的头盔吗?
You're implying something about my helmet?
你怎么看都是邋遢的呆子 既使在科学家堆里
You look like a massive nerd, even around other scientists.
我能问一下... 她甩你的时候你也戴着这头盔?
Can Ijust ask--Were you wearing the helmet while she dumpedyou?
这头盔是保护我这颗重要大脑的 哈伯
See, it protects my very important brain, Harper.
来准备标本吧
Go prep the samples.
- 嘿!找到你了  - 贝蒂 嘿!
- Hey. I found  you.   - Betty, hey.
我讨厌他们
I hate them.
- 等等 我才到这里  - 我们该讨厌什么?评论委员会
- Wait, I just got here.   - Who do we hate? The review board.
我们要在星期二作报告的
We have to make a presentation on Tuesday. Ah.
你要跟我一起做
And you're gonna make it with me.
你认为我应该吗?是的
You think I should? Yeah.
这方面你很有研究
You're great with that stuff.
一提起微生物和奈米医学 你就来劲了
You start talking about microbes and nanomeds, you sound almost... passionate.
对不起
I'm sorry.
无理了
That was rude.
我们曾经那么亲密 在一起工作
Look, nobody expects this to be easy,
没有人指望这会简单
us working together after being... so close.
我们曾经亲密过?
We were close?
如果我能更...
Look, if I could be more...
不管怎么说 你知道...
whatever, you know--
- 我...只是...  - 别
- I'm... just...   - Don't.
这不是你的错 真的
It's not your fault. Really.
我对感情上冷淡的男人 有莫名的眷恋...
You're just a by-product...
你只是其中一个牺牲品
of my inexplicable obsession with emotionally distant men.
我会放下我们的过去的
I'll get over us.
希望如此
Good for you.
不管怎么说 这次评审把我搞的很紧张
Anyway, I'm just really stressed about this review.
如果今天不能取得令人注目的成果
Ifwe don't get impressive results today,
星期二就会很难通过
we're gonna have a really hard sell come Tuesday.
好的 那就让我们作出些什么
Well, then, let's go be impressive.
哈伯
Harper?
- 准备好了  - 我们开始吧
- Readywhen you are.   - Let's hit it.
检查通过了吗?
Are we passing inspection?
保险装置显示一切正常
Safeties all going green.
倒数计时开始
Countdown's started.
奈米医疗组织释放
Nanomeds released.
4秒
Four seconds.
好的 奈米医疗组织完全扩散开了
Okay, nanomeds fully dispersed.
我们加上伽马射线试试
Okay, let's hit Freddie with the gamma radiation.
伽马射线释放
Gamma exposure.
奈米医疗组织很活跃
Nanomeds now active.
奈米医疗组织在外层复制细胞了
Nanomeds replicating cells on border.
起作用了
It's working.
细胞复制与分解比率保持在1%
Cell copyto disassemble ratio holding within one percent.
奈米医疗组织不均衡了
Imbalanced nanomed activity.
你打算周一对评审小组说...
You wanna go to the review board on Monday and tell 'em...
我们发明了一种新的爆破青蛙的方法?
we've developed a brand-new method for exploding frogs?
是的 这也许有市场呢
Yeah, I think maybe there's a market for it.
我是说 也许有瘟疫什么的
I mean, what if there's a plague?
你吃什么 贝蒂 一瓶啤酒?
What have you had, Betty, like, one beer?
我只是说...我只是说 你知道
I'm just sa--I'm just saying, you know,
如果青蛙开始从天上掉下来
frogs start falling from the sky,
他们会找谁帮忙?
who do they come to?
我们会举世闻名
We'd be world-renowned.
令双亲感到骄傲
Make anyparent proud.
我打赌他们会
I bet theywould be.
他们还真希望我成为科学家
They actually did want me to be a scientist.
我是说 你的亲生父母
I mean, your birth parents.
我想我们永远不会知道的
Guess we'll never know.
我不明白 你为什么从不试图找到他们
I don't understand why you don't want to find out about them.
他们死了 他们在我有记忆前就死了
They're dead. They died before I can remember anything.
你总提起这些做什么?
Why do you always come back to this?
我也不知道
Don't know.
我总觉着你有什么东西不愿示人
I guess I figure there's more to you than you like to show.
说出来你又不会少什么
I guess there couldn't be any less.
没错 你看 我们说了一圈又绕回来了
Right. So now we come full circle back to that.
干得好 贝蒂
Nice work, Betty.
贝蒂
Betty.
克兰?
Glen. Hey.
你好
Hi.
你的制服怎么了?
What happened toyour uniform?
哦 我...转业了
Oh, I, uh--I switched over.
我仍然和你父亲一起工作 但...
I'm still working with your father, but--
你知道 军方把所有有意思的项目都转包出去...
Well, you know, the military's subcontracting out all the most interesting work, and--
而且报酬丰厚
Can't argue with a paycheck.
现在基地的所有实验室基本上都归我管了
I basically run all the labs on the base now.
哦
Oh.
嗨 你...
Hey, you're uh--
看起相当不错
you're looking good.
你是遗传学专家
You're the genetics expert.
啊 大学里的美好时光
Ah, the good old college days.
在这里怎么样?
So, how's business?
什么意思?
What do you want?
好吧 我直说
All right, I'll cut to the chase.
我听到一些有意思的传言 是关于你们实验室里研究
I've been hearing interesting things about what you guys are doing here.
你们那台分子设备有不可估量的实用价值
Your little molecular machines have some incredible implications.
来为阿瑟娜工作怎么样?
Howwould you like to comeworkfor Atheon?
可以赚目前十倍的薪水...
Get paid 1 0 times as much as you earn now...
还可以分享专利权
and own a piece ofthe patents.
只要你一句话
You just have to say the word.
两个字...出去
Two words: the door.
将军
General?
进来
Come in.
塔尔博特希望你能看看这个 长官
Talbot wanted you to see this, sir.
是关于阿西娜打算收购 并搬迁到沙漠基地的一家实验室
It's about a lab Atheon is targeting for acquisition and removal to desert base.
为什么不经国安局处理?
Why isn't it going through N.S.C.?
和你的女儿有关 长官
It, uh, concerns your daughter, sir.
对不起
Hi. Sorry.
嗨 贝尼怎么了?他不上夜班了吗?
Hey, what happened to Benny? Is he not working the night shift anymore?
贝尼死了
Benny's dead.
我是新来的
I'm the new guy.
哦
Oh.
- 见到你很高兴  - 我也是
- Good to meet  you.   - Same.
再照一张
Let's try another.
不 待在这
Mmm, no. Stay here.
你看起来无精打采的
I look tired anyway.
但是你看起来气色相当好
Yeah, but you look great.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
那些恶梦
It's these dreams, Doctor.
一直缠绕着我 都是可怕的梦
I keep having them, and they're terrible.
说说你的梦
Tell me aboutyour dream.
从...
Well, it starts--
从记忆开始...我想这是我最早的记忆
it starts with a memory--I think it's my first memory.
我记得的是...
It's this image I have...
那时我只有两岁
from when I was maybe twoyears old.
你觉得这真的是梦吗?
Do you think it's just a dream?
不 我想那是我和父亲
No, I think it's something that happened
生活在沙漠基地时发生的一些事情
when I was living at a desert base with my father.
现在
Anyhow,
梦继续...
the dream goes on and...
突然 我孤单一人
suddenlyI'm alone.
太可怕了
That's terrible.
你知道我永远不会伤害你的
You know I'd never hurt  you.
嗨!
Hey there.
你叫什么名字 小可爱?
What'syourname, darlin'?
你叫什么名字?
Eh? What's your name?
好吧
Okay.
没事了
It's okay.
我要和你谈谈 伊蒂丝
I gotta talk to  you, Edith.
布鲁斯 呆在这别动
Bruce, stay here!
"C...T...G...
"C... T... G...
A...G."
A... G."
布鲁斯
Bruce.
我的布鲁斯
My Bruce.
早安 克兰来拜访我们了
Good morning. Glen dropped by.
他在这里做什么?
What's he doing here?
克伦斯勒博士
You know, Dr. Krenzler,
你跟我一直没合适机会互相了解
you and I have never had the chance to get to know each other properly.
那是因为我不想了解你 不管合适还是不合适
Well, that's because I don't want to get to know  you, properly or improperly.
出去
So leave.
嘿 别紧张
Hey, no worries.
让我来提醒你一下
Let me give you a little heads-up.
善意的邀请和恶意的抢夺...
There is a hairsbreadth between friendly offer...
往往只有一线之差
and hostile takeover.
我调查过了 你们现在的研究非常有价值
I've done my homework. The workyou're doing here is dynamite.
想想...
Think: GIs embedded with technology...
具备在战场上可以即时自愈能力的士兵...
that makes them instantlyrepairable on the battlefield...
只有我们掌控
in oursole possession.
这可是笔大买卖
That's a hell of a business.
这不是我们做这个的目的
Well, it's not what we're doing here.
我们是为普通人作基础科学研究
We're doing the basic science for everyone.
以后我会写本书...
You know, someday I'm gonna write a book...
我会把它称为"愚蠢的理想和聪明但身无分文的科学家"
and I'm gonna call it When Stupid Ideals Happen To Smart, Penniless Scientists.
那时 布鲁斯 你会知道我的利害的
I n the meantime, Bruce, you will be hearing from me.
关于克兰 我...
About Glen, I, um--
没什么可说的
There's nothing to talk about.
好吧
Okay.
我只是想说 别因为他而担心... 我会处理这件事
I just wanted to say, don't worry about him--I'll handle it.
怎样?
How?
我打电话给我父亲
I'm gonna call my father,
给他施加点压力
ask him to exertsome pressure.
但我听说你和你父亲互相不说话
Last I heard, you and your father weren't speaking.
那么...
Well...
我想现在有话题和他谈了
I guess now I have something to talkwith him about.
电路好像出问题了
I think this circuit's kinda fried.
我也不确定 你能来看看吗?
I don't know. Maybe you wanna come take a look at it.
好的 我就来
Okay, I'll be right there.
啊!
Aah!
伽马值太高了 布鲁斯 停不下来了!
The gamma's too high! Bruce, I can't stop it!
哈伯 快出去!
Harper, get out!
出去!
Get out!
哈伯怎么样了?
How's Harper?
他没事
He's all right.
你救了他
You saved him.
我想他短时间不能回实验室了
I don't think he's coming back to the lab for a while, though.
我怎么也想不通
I don't understand how this is possible.
按理说 你应该死了
You should be dead.
那些奈米医疗组织起作用了
Theyworked--the nanomeds.
我感觉好极了
I mean, I feel great.
我觉得...说不清 它们一定...修复了我的身体
I feel like--I don't know. They must have, like, fixed me.
布鲁斯 它们只会杀死所接触到的一切
Bruce, they've killed everything else that they've come into contact with.
你确定医生真的检查过了?
Are you sure the doctor checked?
医生已经给我做了彻底检查
The doctor gave me the full workup.
他还问我怎么会这么好
He wants to know where he can get what I'm taking.
我完全正常
I'm a hundred percent.
甚至...更好
More.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
还记得我受伤的膝盖吗?
Remember my bad knee?
现在它已经完全正常了
Well, now it's my good knee.
布鲁斯 这可不是闹着玩的
Bruce, this isn't funny.
我当时一直在看着你
I was watching  you.
你当时就要死了 而我却眼睁睁看着你死
You were gonna die, and I was gonna have to watch you die.
贝蒂...
Betty...
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的
Really.
嘿 我不会爆开的 相信我好吗?
Hey, I'm not gonna explode. Okay?
对
Yeah.
你应该休息休息
You should get some rest.
我真的很好
And I'm fine. Really.
从来没有这么好过
I've never felt better.
你的名字不是克伦斯勒
Your name is not Krenzler.
而是斑纳
It's Banner.
- 什么?  - 你叫斑纳
- What?   - Your name--it's Banner.
布鲁斯.斑纳
Bruce Banner.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
- 你怎么进来的?  - 我在这里上班
- How did you get in here?   - I work here now.
在实验室 上夜班
In the labs. The late shift.
这样我就能接近你
It keeps me close to you.
你总是和你的朋友萝丝小姐工作到很晚
You always work so lateyourself with your friend Miss Ross.
不 不 请别 让我说完
No, no. Please. Please. Let me.
你还没好
You're not well.
你刚出了可怕的事故
You've had a terrible accident.
你在疑惑为什么你还活着
You're wondering whyyou're still alive.
你在想这肯定有原因
You're thinking there's something inside.
非比寻常...
Something different...
难以解释
inexplicable.
我能帮你搞清楚..
I can help you understand,
如果你能让我...
If you'll let me.
如果你能...
If you'll...
原谅我的话
forgive me.
听着 先生 我肯定没什么需要原谅你的
Look, mister, I'm sure I have nothing to forgive you for.
你还是请回吧
So perhaps you should leave now.
我会好的
I'll be fine.
你一定要知道
You must know.
也许你不愿相信
You may not want to believe it,
但我从你眼里看得出
but I can see it in your eyes.
太像你母亲了
So much likeyour mother's.
这是理所当然的 因为你是我的骨肉
Of course, you're my flesh and blood.
但也还具有其他的东西 不是吗
But then, you're something else too, aren'tyou?
在身体上是我的儿子
My physical son,
在思想上也是
but the child of my mind too.
不
No.
你胡说
You're lying.
我很小的时候 父母就已双亡
My parents died when I was a small boy.
不 这不是真的 那是他们要你相信的
No, no, that's not true. That's what theywanted you to believe.
实验 事故...都是最高机密
The experiments, the accident--all top secret.
他们把我赶走30年
They put me away for 30 years.
30年
Thirtyyears!
远离你
Away from  you.
远离我们的工作
Away from ourwork.
但他们不能永远管制我
But they couldn't keep me forever.
毕竟 我没疯 他们不得不承认这个
After all, I'm sane. They had to admit it.
你知道
You see,
多年来...
everything...
你卓越的头脑一直追寻的...
your extraordinary mind...
所有的东西...
has been seeking all theseyears...
一直在你体内
it's been inside you.
现在 我们要去理解它
Now we will understand it.
我们要驾驭它
We will harness it.
不 别接 一定是萝丝小姐
No, don't answer it. It's Miss Ross again.
你需要知道一些有关她的事情 布鲁斯 一些棘手的事
There's something you need to know about her, Bruce. Something troublesome.
我会保护你免受她的伤害
Let me protect you from her.
不 滚出去!
No. Get out.
- 布鲁斯...  - 滚出去!
- Bruce...   - Get out!
坐下!
Sit!
我们以后得注意点你的脾气
We're gonna have to watch that temper ofyours.
你确定你没事吗?
You sureyou're okay?
没事 只是高兴离开了床
Yeah,just glad to be out ofbed.
从我爸那里接到消息
Got a message from my father.
他要来看我
He's coming to see me.
你父亲?
Your father? Mmm.
什么时候?
When?
一个小时之内降落
Lands in about an hour.
有趣的是 他打了电话给我
The funnything is, he calledme.
- 嗨 爸爸!  - 你好 贝蒂!
- Hi, Dad.   - Hello, Betty.
- 这里 女士  - 谢谢
- Here, ma'am.   - Thanks.
- 别客气 先生  - 谢谢
- You're welcome. Sir?   - Thank you.
别客气
You're welcome.
开门见山
Look, I 'm gonna get right to it.
是关于克兰 是吗?
It's about Glen, isn't it?
他这段时间一直在我的实验室到处刺探
He's been snooping around my lab.
克兰发现了些情况
Glen noticed some things,
要我做些调查
asked me to make some inquiries.
你是来...
Are you here to...
盘问我的?
question me?
不
No.
我们发现些叫人吃惊的事情
We've turned up some surprising things.
和你一起工作的这位 克伦斯勒...
This Krenzler you workwith--
你知道他是谁吗?
you know who he reallyis?
你了解他多少?
How much do you actually know about him?
我觉得问题在于
I think the question is,
你了解他些什么?
what is it that you know about him?
- 现在 我不...  - 不能随便向我泄露 对 对
- Well, right now, I'm not...   - Not at liberty to disclose it to me. Right. Right.
你知道
You know,
我原以为..
I think I was hoping that...
也许这次...
maybe this time you just...
你是真心的来看我
honestlywanted to see me again.
- 你搞错了 贝蒂  - 我搞错了吗?
- You've got this all wrong, Betty.   - Do I?
是的 我真的是想来看你
Yes. I do want to see  you.
我真希望我能相信你
I reallywish that I could believe  you.
多年来...
Everything...
你卓越的头脑一直追寻的...
your extraordinarymind has been seeking...
所有的东西
all theseyears,
一直在你体内
it's been inside  you.
这里是克伦斯勒博士
Hi, you've called Dr. Krenzler.
请留言 我会尽快回覆的
Please leave a message and I'll call you right back.
布鲁斯 嗨!你在吗?
Bruce, hey. Are you there?
我想我搞砸了
Look, um, I think I screwed up.
我父亲...看来他好像对你有些怀疑 我不确定
My father--It's like he suspects you ofsomething. I don 't know.
我就像以往一样很不耐烦
I was so impatient, like always.
没听他说明白 我...
I didn 't hear him out. I don't know, I--
我只是猜测他们对实验室有所企图
Ijust think that they're planning something with the lab.
嗯...
So, um, uh--
打电话给我 好吗?
Call me. Okay?
再见
Bye.
贝蒂?
Betty?
指挥中心!指挥中心!我们在实验室发现415号情况!
Dispatch! Dispatch! We have a 41 5 at the lab!
马上派柏克莱警察局增援!火速增援!
Send Berkeley P.D. now! Send 'em now!
小心
Watch out!
伊迪丝?
Edith?
发生了什么事
David, what's going on?
- 我要和你谈谈 伊迪丝  - 布鲁斯 呆在这里
- I gotta talk to  you, Edith.   - Bruce, stayhere.
我的布鲁斯
My Bruce.
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
那里发生了爆炸
There was some sort of explosion.
他们不让我们进去
Theywouldn't let us into the building.
我当时很担心你
I was worried about you.
嗯...我没事
Well, I'm okay.
你昨晚怎么了?
What happened to you last night?
我做了个好梦
I had the most vivid dream.
就像刚刚诞生
Itwas like being born.
出来迎接空气 光线射到我脸上
Coming up for air. Light hitting myface.
叫嚷着
Screaming.
我的心跳...
My heartbeat--
就像 砰...
itwas, like, boom...
砰...
boom...
砰
boom.
你当时在实验室吗?
Were you at the lab?
不在
No.
但有个东西...
But something--
还有那个男人
And there was that man.
那个带着狗的人
The one with the dogs.
谁
Who?
那个新来的管理员
That new janitor.
他说他是我父亲
He said he was my father.
我去
I'll get it.
我爸爸
My father.
原来这位就是年轻人布鲁斯...
So this is the young Bruce Ban--
克伦斯勒
Krenzler.
我想你昨晚留了些东西在实验室
I think you left something in your lab last night.
雷切尔
Mitchell.
护送我女儿出去 我待会就出去
Escort my daughter outside. I'lljoin hershortly.
我宁愿留在这里
I'd rather stay here.
马上!贝蒂
Now, Betty.
没事的
It's okay.
我会没事的
I 'll be fine.
看住他 我就回来
Keep him under observation. I 'll be back.
- 什么  - 你那位朋友
- What?   - Your friend in there.
他很有可能因为一些大案被抓
There's a good chance he's caught up in some very bad business.
未遂的大案
Unfinished business.
我向你保证 我会彻底查出真相
And I promise you, I'm gonna get to the bottom ofit.
我向你保证 我保证他会被照顾的很好
You have myword I'll make sure he's cared for.
但现在 他要被监禁
But as of right now, he is incommunicado.
至少这几天
And for the next few days at least,
你得远离这里
you're gonna stay away from here.
这是为你好
Foryour own good.
好 这是那值夜班的新人的 是吗?
Okay, and that's for the new guy on the night shift, right?
太好了 谢谢 太感激了
Great. Thank you. I appreciate it.
萝丝博士
Dr. Ross.
意料之外
How unexpected.
请进
Please come in.
对不起 我突然来访
I'm sorry to just show up at your house like this.
我想要问你的事...
I came to ask you something that...
是我不该问的
I really have no business asking.
他告诉你了
He told you?
他说你和他谈过
He said you talked to him.
请坐
Please sit down.
布鲁斯昨晚在实验室 他说你也在那里
Brucewas at the lab last night. He said that you were there too.
但是他对细节记不清楚了
But he can't remember much about it.
我想知道发生什么
I needto findout what happened.
你想知道
So,you want to know, uh,
他怎么了...
what's wrong with him...
好治疗他
so you can fix him?
医好他 改变他
Cure him, change him.
我爸爸是军方的
My father's with the military.
他好像认为他威胁国家安全
He seems to think he's involved in some kind of threat to national security.
你父亲 萝丝
Yourfather. Ross.
你会危害到你父亲的
You broughtyourfather down upon his head?
你所知甚少 萝丝小姐
How little you understand, Miss Ross,
你的无知非常危险
and how dangerous your ignorance has become.
- 抱歉 你什么意思  - 不要抱歉
- I'm sorry.   - Don't be sorry.
我的儿子...
Myson is...
与众不同
unique.
这就是为什么你不能和他有关联
That's why you can't relate to him.
而且因为他的与众不同
Andbecause he is unique,
这个世界是不会容忍他的存在的
the world will not tolerate his existence.
他们会吗
Will they?
但你...
But you--
你尝试了
you try,
是吗?
don't you?
对
Yes.
像你这样一个美丽的女人
And a very beautiful woman like  you,
你的慇勤...
your attentions...
不会完全被忽略的
can't be completely unwanted.
对吗?
Can they?
不
No.
不会对着你这样的眼睛
Not with eyes like yours,
这样顾盼流连
watching expectantly,
情深切切
Iovingly.
恐怕我们现在很难帮到他了
But I'm afraid we're both too late to help him.
我无能为力 对他...
There's nothing I can do for him...
或对你
or for you.
另外
Besides,
他已声明 他不想与我有任何关系
he's made it clear he wants nothing to do with me.
这是他的选择
His choice.
如果你能原谅我 萝丝小姐 我还有事要做
Now, If you'll excuse me, Miss Ross, I have some work to do.
别怕那些狗
And don't worry about the dogs.
没事的
You'll be fine.
只要别直视它们的眼睛就行
Just don't look 'em in the eyes.
再见
Good-bye.
他获释了 而一个月后 你的实验室就被毁了
He gets released, anda month later yourlab is destroyed.
太巧合了吧!
What a coincidence.
你不会告诉我他现在在那里 是吗
So you're not gonna tell me where he is, are ya?
我跟你说了多少次了 我想帮你 但我真的不知道
How many times do I have to tell you? I'd like to help  you, but I just don't know.
你知道我的身份 斑纳?
You know who I am. Right, Banner?
- 你是贝蒂的父亲 你是高级将军  - 废话少说
- Your Betty's father. You're a high-ranking general.   - Let's cut the crap.
我就是那个把你父亲关起来的人 像对他一样
I'm the guywho had your father tossed away, and a lot more like him,
如果我觉得有必要 我也会干掉你的?
and I'll do the same with you if l feel so disposed.
你明白?
You understand?
你把他关起来 那你还问我干什么?
If you had him tossed away, then why are you asking me?
我不记得了 过去人们一直对我说我父亲已经死了
I don't remember. I was always told my fatherwas dead.
别和我兜圈
Don't playwith me!
你看到那情景时 你已经四岁了
You were fouryears old when you saw it.
什么时候?我看见什么?
When I saw what?
你当时在场 那样的情景谁会忘得一干二净
You were right there. How could anyone forget a thing like that?
什么?
What?
又是记忆受压抑
Oh, some more repressed memories.
快告诉我
Just tell me.
抱歉 小子
I'm sorry, son.
你比我想像的还要混蛋
You're an even more screwed-up mess than I thoughtyou'd be.
在我们搞清楚一切之前
Until we get to the bottom ofthis,
你的实验室被列为一级军事禁区...
yourlab has been declared a top-secret militarysite...
而且你没有安全许可再进去...
and you're not gonna get a security clearance to get back into it...
或任何一个研究范围超出
or any other lab that's doing anything more interesting than...
下一代草本发胶...的实验室
... trying to figure out the next generation ofherbal hair gel.
还有件事
One more thing.
如果你胆敢...
If you ever...
再次出现在我女儿一千码内的范围内
come within a thousand yards of my daughter again,
我将会给你终生监禁
I'll put you away for the rest ofyour natural life.
狗
Dogs!
去!抓住她
Go! Go get her!
没什么能阻挡你们
And let nothing stand in yourway!
去
Go!
你好?
Hello?
布鲁斯
Bruce?
他们以为可以将你也关起来 就像他们对付我那样
So, they think they can just throw you away as they did me.
我有什么问题 你对我做了什么?
What's wrong with me? What did you do to me?
我今天有个访客
I got a visit today.
一个非常不受欢迎的访客
A very unwelcome visit.
恐怕我不得不这么做了
I'm afraid my hand is being forced.
你对我做了什么
What did you do to me?
你很想知道 是吗
You so much want to know, don'tyou?
但我想 没有什么解释比..
But I think no explanation will serve you halfas well..
亲身体验更有效
as the experience.
无论如何 我自己也还不太明白
In any case, I still don't quite understand it myself.
如果他们能让我安静地工作...
Ifthey'd only let me work in peace--
当然 我的老上级也不会这么想
Of course, my betters would have none ofthat.
你在自己身上做试验 是不是
So you experimented onyourself, didn'tyou?
再传给我... 到底是什么?
And passed on to me... what?
一种变异 基因变异
An alteration. Genetic.
畸形 我想你也可以这么说
A deformity. I guess you could call it that.
但是那也是种令人惊讶的力量
But an amazing strength too.
现在终于释放出来了 我能够收获了
And now, finally unleashed, I can harvest it.
不
No.
不会让你得逞的
You'll do no such thing.
我会提取这东西 治好我自己
I will isolate it and treat it myself.
我会在它造成真正伤害前把它清除 消灭掉
I'll remove it and I'll kill it before it does any real harm.
我打赌你和贝蒂都热衷于毁灭掉它
I'll bet you and your Betty would love to destroy it.
但是你真的能毁掉你身体的一部分吗
But would you really destroy part ofyourself?
我可不这么认为
I don't think so.
至于贝蒂
And as for Betty,
我有几个四条腿的朋友...
I'm sending her a surprise visit...
正赶去访问她
from some four-legged friends of mine.
我已经培养了你的一些基因 布鲁斯
You see, I managed to culture some ofyourvery own DNA, Bruce,
结果很惊人
and the results are tremendous.
它们相当不稳定 但是力量很强大
They're unstable, but very powerful.
我的基因怎么了
What about my DNA?
我们等等贝蒂的结果就知道了
Let's just wait and see what Betty makes ofthe results, huh?
不 你疯了
No. You're crazy.
我不会让你得逞的
I won't let you.
- 把手拿开  - 这是什么意思...
- Getyour hands off of me.   - Talbot, what's this--
进去 混蛋 我要跟你谈谈
Inside, asshole. I wanna talk to you.
听着 我父亲要暗算贝蒂...
Listen, myfather's going after Betty--
你以为可以在背后暗算我 让萝丝把我调走 哈?
What makes you think you can go behind my back and get Ross to cut me out, huh?
听着!贝蒂有麻烦了
Listen to me! Betty's in trouble!
你这个可怜的傻瓜!
You pathetic freak.
贝蒂有危险了 我发誓 她会死的!
Betty's in danger. I swear to  you, she'll be killed.
明显的是
I can state the obvious.
你已经不在重要的位置上 不能再威胁别人了
Something tells me you aren't in much ofa position to be making stupid threats to anyone.
嗯?
Talbot. Yeah?
你把我惹恼了
You're making me angry.
哦 是吗?
Oh, am I?
我看到他了!开火!
I got him! Open fire!
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
他派来的狗 是吗?
He sent these dogs, didn't he?
但我把他们杀了
But I killed them!
天哪!
My God.
一定是因为奈米医疗组织 一定是因为伽马射线
It must be the nanomeds. It must be the gamma exposure.
可我们从没见过这种作用
Butwe've never seen any effect like this before.
不 还有更深层的原因
No. Deeper.
伽马射线不过激发了原来就有的东西
The gamma just unleashed what was already there.
激发了什么?
Unleashed what?
我
Me.
它
It.
没事了
It's okay.
Shh. It's okay.
那些是什么动物?
What were those animals?
是我父亲派来的
Myfathersent them.
他的确是我父亲
He is my father.
他想让我改变
He wanted me to change.
他想让我变成那个没脑子的怪物
He wanted me to change into that mindless hulk.
但为什么他要这么做?
Whywould he want that?
你还能记起什么?
Can you remember anything?
任何变身之后的事情吗?
Is there anything from when you were changed?
就像一场梦
It was like a dream.
什么梦?
About what?
愤怒
Rage.
力量
Power.
和自由
And freedom.
喂?长官
Hello? Sir.
爸爸
Hello. Dad?
贝蒂!你没事吧?
Betty! Are you all right?
我吓坏了 我需要你的帮助
I'm scared. I need your help.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
你还好吗?
How are you?
还好 我猜
Okay, I guess.
我想...
I think that somehow...
愤怒触发了你身体里的奈米医疗组织
your anger is triggering the nanomeds.
怎么会?我们的设计是对物理伤害起反应
How could it? We designed them to respond to physical damage.
精神伤害有时会转化到物理上
Emotional damage can manifest physically.
比如说?
Like what?
严重的精神创伤
Serious trauma.
压抑的记忆
Repressed memories.
你父亲盘问过我小时候的事...
Your father grilled me about something that happened to me from early childhood...
一些我应该记得的事
that I'm supposed to remember.
是吗?
He did?
听起来挺糟糕的 但...我真的不记得了
It sounded bad, but... I honestly don't remember.
让我担心的...
The thing that worries me...
是...
is...
物理上伤害是有限的
a physical wound is finite,
但是精神上的
but with emotions,
会不会一直持续下去...
what's to sayit won't just go on and on...
产生连锁反应?
and start a chain reaction?
你知道我最害怕的是什么事情吗?
You know what scares me the most?
当那发生时
When it happens,
当那个又来时...
when it comes over me...
当我完全失去了控制时
and I totally lose control,
但我却很喜欢这感觉
I like it.
别担心 我在这儿 抱歉
It's okay. I got  you. I'm sorry.
你会没事的 只是让你睡一会
You'll be okay. It's just to make you sleep.
目标被击倒 目标已无威胁
Target down. Target secure.
我会带你去安全的地方
I'm going to take you someplace safe.
好不好?布鲁斯?
Okay? Bruce?
布鲁斯?
Bruce?
好了!
Clear!
- 立正!  - 继续
- Attention on deck.   - Carry on.
我们在这荒漠下
We're buried out here in the middle ofnowhere.
你想让他这样不省人事多久?
How long are you gonna keep him sedated?
他的余生 如果不得不的话
For the rest of his natural life, if I have to.
- 你说过我能相信你  - 我是你的父亲
- You said I could trust  you.   - I 'm your father.
你可以信任我认为正确的事 而不是你认为对的
You can trust me to do what I think is right, not what you think you want.
- 他是个人  - 他也是别的东西
- He is a human being.   - He is also something else.
设想一下他逃出去 在人口密集的地方...
Suppose he gets out, has one ofhis little mood swings...
耍耍脾气
in a populated area.
我知道那种潜在的危险 但我也知道他救了我的命
Yes, I'm aware of the potential danger. I'm also aware that he saved my life.
没错 把你从那些变种的狗那里救出来
Yeah, from a mutant French poodle.
这是我欠他的
I'm indebted to him for that.
但他也让三个人躺在医院里 塔尔伯特几乎不能走路
He also put three men in a hospital, and Talbot's barelywalking!
你究竟想让我做什么?
What do you want me to do?
我想让你帮帮他
I want you to help him!
为什么他对你有这么大的威胁?
Why is he such a threat toyou?
因为我知道他是从哪里来的
Because I knowwhat he comes from.
他是他父亲的儿子 他的每一部分都像他父亲那样
He is his father's son, every last molecule ofhim.
他说他不认识他的父亲
Hesays he doesn't know his father,
可他偏偏和他父亲工作在同一研究领域
but he's workin' in the same exact goddamn field his father did.
所以 要不是他在撒谎...或者更糟 他...
So either he's lyin'... or it's somethin' worse, and he's--
什么?
What?
命中注定要继承他父亲的事业?
Predestined to follow in his father's footsteps?
我本想说"受诅咒的"
I was gonna say "damned."
当然你会这么想
Of course you were.
但我是个科学家
But I'm a scientist.
作为一个科学家 我相信可以找到解决办法帮助他
As a scientist, I believe we can figure this out and he can be helped.
我知道你会的
I know you do.
不管你知不知道 在不在意
Look, whether you know or care,
我为你做的一切感到自豪
I've got a lot of pride in what you've done.
但这事关重大 不是你能做的
But this is too big for you.
听着 我知道政府以为他们掌握了一件武器
Look, I know the government thinks they have a weapon on their hands.
不然 他早就死掉了
Otherwise, he'd be dead by now.
他们可以任意研究他们想知道的东西
They can probe andprod all they want,
但现在 让我来试着帮助他
and in the meanwhile, just let me try to help him.
没有人比我更了解他
Nobodyknows him betterthan I do.
大卫·斑纳 你对他做了什么?
What did David Banner do to him?
- 掩护左边!  - 左边没危险
- Cover left!   - Clear left.
掩护右边!
Cover right!
发生什么事了?
What's happening here?
我的手
My hand.
我儿子基因的力量...
Yousee, thestrength ofmyson's DNA...
结合奈米医疗组织重建...
combined with nanomed reconstruction--
我能够融合任何东西
You see, I can partake with the essences of all things.
要你把手...
Gonna have to ask you to...
举起来 朋友 好么?
put your hands up, pal, okay?
放松 慢慢来
Nice and easy.
你真的认为...
Do you really believe...
我和你是分开的吗?
that I am separate from you?
我在什么地方?
Where am I?
在家
You're home.
难以相信我们以前住在这里
It's hard to believe we used to live here.
我肯定曾经见过你...或是认识你
I must have seen you or known  you.
只要我能记起来
If only I could remember.
这里以前是我的家 对不对?
This is my old house, isn't it?
走吧
Let's go.
再试试
Please try.
怎么了?
What is it?
没什么
Nothing.
真的?!
Really?
妈的
Damn it.
好吧 贝蒂 你想知道什么?
Okay, Betty... what do you want to know?
那房间里有什么?
What was in that room?
你到底在害怕我会看见什么?
What are you afraid that I'll see?
看 什么也没有
See? There's nothing.
是空的
It's empty.
你什么意思 我无权见他?
What do you mean, I don't have access to him?
国家安全局已经决定把这个威胁的研究交给阿瑟娜
NSA has decided to turn overstudy ofthe, uh--the threat to Atheon.
但你是这个基地的头
But you're head of the base.
我还以为这个基地归你管
I thought you were in charge.
可我不能制定政策 我也得听命于人
But I don't set policy, and I still take orders.
真难以相信塔尔伯特居然这样对我!
I can't believe Talbot would go around me like this!
很多有权力的人都想接手这件事情
Oh, there's a lot of powerful people that want in on this.
他们都想从中牟利
And moneyto be made--lots ofit.
你知道最糟的是什么吗?
You know the worst part about all this?
当把大卫.班纳关起来 把那孩子送走时
When I had David Bannerlocked up andsent that kid away,
我没注意这小子: 我认为他只不过是个无辜的受害者
I didn't give that boy a second thought: he was just collateral damage.
但现在他不再是了 是不是?
Well, he isn't anymore, is he?
我还可以做什么?
What can I do?
你可以回家去
You can go home now.
我也希望你能去和他道别 我已经接到通知...
I'd tell you to go andsaygood-bye, but I've alreadybeen informed...
现在任何接触都是不允许的
that for now all further contact is out of the question.
好吧
Right.
嗨 布鲁斯 感觉如何?伙食合你口味吗?
Hiya, Bruce. How ya feelin'? Grub okay in here forya?
你想怎么样?
What do you want?
嗯 问得好
That's a good question.
嗯 我需要你的细胞做些实验
See, I need your cells to trigger some chemical distress signals.
你能否为我再"绿"一次...
You know, so you can turn a little green for me again...
好让我从真正的"你"身上切些肉
and I can carve off a piece ofthe real  you,
分析一下 搞个专利 再赚个大钱
analyze it, patent it, make a fortune.
你不介意吧?
Do you mind?
我不会让你如愿的
I'll never let you.
我觉得你没别的选择
I'm not sureyou've got much ofa choice.
来吧 布鲁斯 你难道不愤怒吗?
Come on, Bruce. Aren't you feeling a little angry?
毕竟 现在只有我陪你玩了
After all, you've only got me to playwith now that Betty's dumped you and gone back to Berkeley.
贝蒂已经抛弃你返回柏克莱了
你说谎
You're lying.
你知道 对我来说 这是个双赢的局面
You know, for me this is a win-win situation.
你一变绿 外面那些家伙就会冲进来杀了你...
You turn green, andall these guys come in and kill you...
然后我就可以解剖你
and I perform the autopsy.
假如你不变绿的话...
You don't...
我就拿你擦地...
and I mop the floor with  you...
也许一不小心 弄断你的脖子
and maybe by accident go too far and breakyour neck.
虽然对研究来说可能不太好... 但我个人会很爽
Bad science, maybe... but personally gratifying.
快点嘛 布鲁斯!让我们看看你的能耐
Come on, Bruce! Let's see what you got.
休想
Never.
你的意识想控制自己
You know, consciously you may control it,
但是你的潜意识就是另一回事了
but subconsciously, I bet that's another story.
好吧 开动脑电波吧
All right, let's jump-start those brain waves.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
亲爱的萝丝小姐
My dear Miss Ross.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
外面有两个警卫
There are two guards right outside.
别担心 我已经不再生你的气了
You don't have to worry. I'm not angrywith  you. Not anymore.
你想怎样?
What do you want?
我基本上已经完了 我知道
It's overforme now. I knowthat.
布鲁斯也快了
And soon it'll be over for Bruce.
所以我来找你
That's why I've come to you--
问你能否劝说你父亲
to ask you If you could persuade your father,
作为一个人 也作为一个父亲
as a man, as a father himself,
现在如果我能自首 和平地...
that ifl turn myselfin now, peacefully...
在他将我永远地关起来之前
and before he puts me away forever,
能不能让我见我的孩子...
that he would let me see my son...
最后一面
for one last time.
你能帮我这个忙吗?
Could you do that for me?
这件事现在已经不归我父亲管了
It's out of my father's hands now.
我明白 他现在是个傀儡了
I understand. He's a puppet now.
- 我不会怪他  - 你也不应该
- I don't blame him.   - Youshouldn't.
你应该对你儿子做的事情感到愧疚
You should blameyourself forwhat you've done toyour son.
萝丝小姐 我对我儿子做什么了?
And what have I done to my son, Miss Ross?
什么也没做 我只不过尽力想改善我自己
Nothing. I tried to improve on the limits in myself.
我自己 不是他
Myself!. Not him!
你明白吗?改善本质
Can you understand? To improve on nature.
我的自然本质 对自己的认知
My nature! Knowledge of oneself! It's the only path to the truth...
这才是走向真理
that give men the power to go beyond God's boundaries!
给人类突破到神的境界的力量的唯一道路
你知道你极限之外是什么吗?其他人
You know what's beyond your boundaries? Other people.
你留给布鲁斯的只有恐惧
Allyou've given Bruce is fear.
对生活的恐惧
Fear of life.
恐惧
Fear?
也许吧 萝丝小姐
Perhaps, Miss Ross.
还有孤独
And loneliness too.
没错...这些我都能感受到
Yes... I feel them both.
但是 我也曾真正地生活过
But I have lived... completely once.
我也曾深陷爱河
I was so much in love,
而她非常想要个孩子
andshe so much wanteda baby.
我的孩子
Mybaby.
就在她怀孕的时候开始 我感觉到...
I could tell from the moment she conceived...
我给她的不是一个儿子...
that it wasn't a son I had given her...
而是别的东西
but something else.
也许是一个怪物
A monster, maybe.
我那时就应该阻止这一切的发生
I should have put a stop to it right then,
但是我也很好奇 所以这也是我失败的开始
but I was curious and that was my downfall.
我看着这个小生命慢慢的成长
And as I watched this tiny life unfold,
我开始想像以后可能出现的可怕场景
I began to imagine the horror ofit,
好奇心终于被...
and my curiosity was replaced...
同情取代
with com passion.
然而他们剥夺了我治愈他的权力
But they took away my chance to cure him.
你父亲把我赶出来
Your father threw me out.
- 你在做什么?  - 那一天 我还是记忆犹新...
- What are you doing?   - I remember that dayso well...
每一刻 每个感觉...
every moment, every sensation...
走进屋子
walking into the house,
手里握着刀柄的感觉
the feeling ofthe handle ofthe knife in my hand.
我知道我在尽一个父亲的义务 履行一个父亲的仁慈
I knew I was doing a father's work, fulfilling a father's mercy.
大卫 不!不!大卫 住手!
David, please stop it! No!
大卫 听我说!
David, no! Talk to me! Listen!
然而她让我很惊讶
But then she surprised me.
不!不!!
No! No!
大卫!不!
David, no!
好像..
It was as if..
她和那把刀...
she and the knife...
融合了
merged.
不!
No!
你无法想像...
You cannot imagine...
那令人断肠的结局
the unbearable finality ofit.
在那一刻...
And in that one moment...
我毁了我爱的一切...
I took everything that was dear to me...
留下的...
and transformed it into nothing more...
只有回忆
than a memory.
很好 他刚才一定作了恶梦
Bi ngo! That m ust be some jum bo nightmare he just had.
开始 从酵素提取开始
Okay, do it now. Start the enzyme extraction.
长官 钻机穿不破
Sir, negative on drill penetration.
妈的 加大功率 最大转速!加油!伙计!继续!
Damn it, drill him harder! Give him full RPMs. Come on, Holeman! Come on!
要取消操作吗?
Should I neutralize?
不!一堆粘液对我来说没用!继续!
No! I can't do anything with goop! Come on!
好吧 让他睡觉!
All right, put him to sleep.
不起作用!
It's not stopping him!
把防卫队派来
Ready room, send in our containment team.
非致命武器 我重申 只用非致命武器!
Non-lethals only. I repeat, non-lethals only.
我要取他身体的样本!
I must have a sample ofhim.
长官
Sir!
- 天啊  - 用泡沫对付他!
- Jesus!   - Hit him with the foam.
释放抑制泡沫
Deploycontainment foam.
塔尔博特 请讲话
Talbot, talk to me.
停火!
Cease fire!
都在控制中 将军 有需要我会通知你的
Under control, General. I'll let you know ifwe need  you.
不行 马上撤退到这里
Unacceptable. Unseat your asses down here immediately.
我要全体疏散
I want a full-court evacuation now.
- 我要把你们那里关闭  - 封锁
- I'm shutting you down.   - Lockdown.
- 你没听到将军说的话吗?  - 我说封锁
- Didn't you hear what the general said?   - I said lockdown!
让开!让我来取样本!
Clear! I need a sample ofhim!
别紧张 伙计
Take it easy there, buddy.
可能会有点痛 布鲁斯
This might give you a bit ofa sting here, Bruce.
- 撤退!撤退!  - 卸掉子弹!卸掉
- Fall back! Fall back!   - Clearyourweapon! Clear it!
给我M2 再见了 大家伙
Give me the M2. So long, big boy.
马上封锁整个基地
Lockdown the entire facility immediately.
目标仍向蓝区移动
Target's still moving towards blue level.
疏散主厅
Evacuate the main hall.
后备队支援 要重型武器 一级警戒
Send in backup, heavyweapons. Issue general quarters.
在左右设火力点
Set firing lines left and right!
重型武器 快
Heavyweapons, go, go, go!
有危险物泄漏 长官 系统指示危险
Contamination, sir. System readings are redline.
数据在备用能源上
Data's on backup power supply.
小心!
Incoming!
- 切断大厅所有电源  - 长官?
- Shut down all power to the main hall.   - Sir?
给他留出去的路 我们去外面收拾他
Show him the way out. We'll fight him outside.
驾驶员 停下!驾驶员 停下!
Driver, stop. Driver, stop.
左面!左面
Gunner, traverse left! Traverse left!
总统先生 我有些坏消息
Mr. President, I have some bad news, sir.
说吧 将军
Let's have it, General.
我已经向总统作了那个怒汉简报 你要说的是这事吧
I've briefed the president onAngryMan. I assume that's what this is about.
是的 女士 我希望获得国家特许授权
It is, ma'am. I'm requesting a National Command Authority override.
怒汉很危险
Angry Man is unsecure.
我要一切力量听我指挥来阻止他
I need everything we have at my disposal in order to stop his movement.
你考虑了平民伤亡吗 将军?
You're expecting civilian casualties, General?
如果我成功阻止他的话 夫人
Not ifl can help it, ma'am.
放手做吧 随时汇报
Consider it done. Keep us posted.
联络控制中心
Contact Goodman Control.
把资料传给各单位
Patch data to the assets.
联络总部
Contact H.Q.
让他们发布紧急疏散令...
Have them initiate an immediate evacuation...
疏散座标653-216的人员...
in vicinity ofgrid coordinates 653-216...
确认已疏散
Confirm that the area has been cleared.
确认那地区已疏散
Confirm area cleared.
总部确认那地区已疏散 各单位就绪 长官
H.Q. confirms area cleared. Assets on-line, sir.
先生们 该去收拾他了
Gentlemen, it's time to dig in.
我要目标停止活动
I want this target stopped in his tracks.
天啊
J esus.
求救 求救!啊...妈的!
Mayday! Mayday! Ah, shit!
探戈四号坠毁 要求C-SAR支援 越快越好
Tango Four is down. Have C-SAR respond to our 20 ASAP.
我们没事 但 在他把我们撕碎前引开
We're okay, but, damn it, get him offus before he tears us apart!
没法射击 你有角度射击吗?
I've got no shot. Do you have a clear line offire?
小心 探戈斗士
Watch it, Tango Flight.
小心左面 左面!
Break left! Break left!
探戈三号后撤 准备地狱火导弹
Tango Three, pull back and set up for a Hellfire shot.
把他引开之前不要开火
Holdyour fire till we draw him off.
探戈一号就位 炮手待命
Tango One is hot. Gun wazzed.
收到 准备好了 准备射击
Roger. Going hot. Guns ready.
任意开火
Engage at will.
探戈一号 退下!挡住我的射击角度了!
Tango One, pull back! Clear my line!
探戈机队 后撤 他已经被我的地狱火锁定
Tango Flight, clear back. I've got him painted for Hellfire.
知道了 开火吧
Roger that. Tango One clear. Take the shot.
探戈一号 探戈三号 我击中目标了
Tango One, Tango Three. I have contact.
妈的!他抓住了我的导弹!
Holy shit! He 's got my missile!
求救 求救!
Mayday! Mayday!
求救 求救!我们被击中!我们在坠落
Mayday! Mayday! We're hit! We're goi ng down!
清点一下伤亡
Give me a head count.
探戈三号 回报战情
Tango Three, give me a sit rep.
我们的飞机挂了 但我们没事
Our kite's busted up, but we're okay.
探戈斗士 你还能看见目标吗?
Tango Flight, do you have eyes on the target?
我看见他进入了巨石群
Tango One. I have him in the rocks.
集中火力 把那里扫荡成停车场
Salvo all. Turn it into a parking lot.
指挥 您的停车场造好了!
T-bolt, your parking lot is ready.
我们没有弹药和燃油了 回基地
We 're bingo for fuel and ammo. R. T.B.
指挥 这里是指挥中心
T-bolt, this is Goodman Control.
目标未被摧毁 他又在移动了
Be advised, target not destroyed. He 's on the move again.
妈的
Dam n!
我找到他了
I 've got it.
看上去他正在回家的路上
I t appears he's headi ng home.
快速反应队
Launch fast movers.
中途拦截摧毁他
Have them intercept and engage.
喂?
Hello?
贝蒂 布鲁斯逃出来了 他正向你那边去...
Betty, Bruce got out. He's headed your way...
应该是去找你的
and probably right for  you.
你离基地有多远
How far from the base are you?
我已经到了 他们正把他父亲带进来
I'm already here. They're taking his father in now.
全是好消息 待在那里 贝蒂
That's all goodnews. Staythere, Betty.
旧金山61英哩 柏克莱65英哩
- 传奇一号就位  - 传奇二号到左面
- Legend One rolling in hot.   - Legend Two breaking offleft.
我认为可以绕回去攻击
I think I can come back around for a gun attack.
找到目标 自由开火
Acquire a clear target. Fire at will.
提升高度 民航机接近
I ncrease altitude. Civilian aircraft in vicinity.
拉起来!拉起来!你要撞到桥了
Pull up! Pull up! You're headed for the bridge!
拉不起来!拉不起来!
I can't pull up! I can't pull up!
你抓住他了 把他带去世界之巅吧
Okay, you've got him now. Take him on a ride to the top of the world.
看看他在稀薄的空气里会怎样
Let's see what the thin air will do forhim.
启动后燃系统
Initiating afterburner.
我已经爬升到600
I'm passing flight level 600.
已经超过我的极限了
This is out of my envelope.
坚持住 传奇号
Hang in there, Legend.
我无法保持高度 他在我的整流罩上了
I can't maintain. He's all over my aerodynamics.
他会比你先失去知觉的
He'll lose consciousness before you.
950 我保持不了了 我要回去了
Nine-fifty. I can't hold it. I'm pulling back!
弱小的人类
Puny human.
看到目标 目标在水中 所有单位准备开火
Contact. He's in the water. All units, weapons hot.
这次不能存侥幸心理
Let's not take any chances.
传奇机队开火 摧毁目标
You are cleared to fire on target, Legend.
- 爸爸  - 贝蒂
- Dad?   - Betty?
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
我必须毁灭他
I have to destroy him.
但你做不到的
But you can't.
你只会更加激怒他 这会让他变得更加强壮
You will only fuel his rage, and you will make him stronger.
他的目标是你 你知道的
It's you he's coming for. You know that.
那么就让我去见他
Then let me go to him.
求你
Please.
给他一个平静下来的机会
Just give him a chance to calm down.
所有在旧金山附近的飞机注意 这里是指挥
All aircraft vicinity ofSan Francisco, this is T-bolt on guard.
这片空域被划为禁飞区
This area has been declared restricted airspace.
所有的飞机马上离开这个地区
Allaircraft are ordered to clearthe airspace immediately.
收到 武器准备完毕
Echo, One-niner. Weapons are hot.
锁定目标 等待攻击命令
Target acquired. Waitingyour orders to engage.
重复 等待攻击命令
Repeat, waiting your orders to engage.
黄色警戒 停止开火 等候命令
Com mand code yel low. Hold for authorization.
所有单位 停止开火
All units, hold your fire.
这里是指挥 所有单位停止射击
This is T-bolt to all assets. You have direct orders to holdyourfire.
重复一遍 停止射击
I repeat, holdyour fire.
收到
Echo, One-niner. Roger that.
快 快 快 快!
Go go, go, go, go, go!
停止射击 直到我下令
Holdyourfire until my command!
24号汇报 到达指定地点
Engine 24 to command. We are in position now.
你找到我了
You found me.
你并不是那么难找
You weren't that hard to find.
不 我是很难找的
Yes, I was.
跟我走
Let's take a walk.
就这样 先生们 他在基地待着...
That's the deal, gentlemen. He stays on this base...
直到我们从中心那里 收到怎样处理他的命令
until we get the final word from C-3 on how to dispose of him.
现在 如果他不乖乖地坐在椅子上
In the meantime, ifhe does anything but sit there in that chair,
我们一开电流 他马上就会被烧成灰
we're gonna turn on the juice and he'll be incinerated immediately.
我们设置了200码的警戒线 长官
We've established a 200-yard perimeter, sir.
如果我们动用电磁阵 不会造成间接伤害的
Ifwe deploy the electromagnetic array, there should be no collateral damage.
他们来了
Here theycome!
贝蒂 我这么做全是为了你
I'm doin' this for you, Betty.
但是不管怎样 我们必须做最坏的打算
But one way or another, we're gonna have to prepare for the worst.
我早该杀掉你
I should have killed  you.
我也早该杀掉你
And I should have killed  you.
我希望你真的这么作了
I wish you had.
昨晚我看见她了
Isawherlast night.
看见她的脸
Saw her face.
褐色的头发
Brown hair.
褐色的眼睛
Brown eyes.
她对我微笑
She smiled at me.
她俯下身来亲吻我的面颊
She reached down and kissed my cheek.
我仍能记得她身上的味道
I can almost remember a smell.
就像沙漠中的鲜花
Almost like desert flowers.
她最喜欢的香水
Her favorite perfume.
这就是我的母亲 我甚至不知道她的名字
It's my mother, and I don't even know her name.
没关系 儿子 哭出来吧
It's all right, son. You go ahead and cry.
哭出来吧
Go ahead and cry.
哭出来就好了
Cry. Crying will do you good.
不要碰我
Don't touch me!
也许你曾是我的父亲
Maybe once you were my father,
但你现在不是了 以后也永远不会
butyou're not now and you neverwill be.
是这样吗?
Oh, is that so?
我有个消息要告诉你 我不是来这里看你的
Well, I got news for you. I didn't come here to see you.
我来这是看我的儿子
I came here to see my son.
我真正的儿子
My real son.
在你身体中的那个
The one inside of you.
你只是一个空壳
You're nothing but a superficial shell,
有一层薄薄的...
a husk offlimsy consciousness...
随时会被破碎的意识
readyto be torn off at a moment's notice.
你怎么想都可以 我不在乎 快滚吧
You can thinkwhat you like. I don't care.Just go!
不 儿子 听我说 我找到了治愈..
No, son. Listen to me. I found a cure.
...我的方法
For me.
我的细胞也能变化
My cells can transform too,
吸收了大量的能量
absorb enormous amounts of energy.
但不像你的 它们并不稳定
But, unlike you, they're unstable.
儿子 我需要你的力量
Son, I need your strength.
我给了你生命
I gave you life.
现在你必须把它还给我...
Now you must give it back to me!
...唯一的百万年代 更多的光芒 更多的力量
Only a million times more radiant, more powerful!
- 停下  - 停下?停下什么?
- Stop it.   - Stop? Stop what?
停下什么?
Stop what?
像外面那些穿制服的人...
Think about all those men out there in their uniforms...
飞扬跋扈 盲目服从
barking and swallowing orders,
把他们自以为是的管制强加给全世界
inflicting their petty rule over the entire globe!
想想他们造成的伤害
Think ofall the harm they've done!
对你!对我!
Toyou! To me!
对全人类!
To humanity!
想像一下...我们能够...
And know this--that we can make them...
在弹指间让他们的国旗 国歌 政府...
andtheirflags and theiranthems and theirgovernments...
灰飞烟灭!
disappear in a flash!
你在我体内
You in me.
我宁愿去死
I'd rather die.
那是你的回答吗?
Oh, that'syouranswer?
那么你应该死去...
Then indeed you shall die... and be reborn...
以一个在虚伪宗教和文明污染人类灵魂前...
a hero... of the kind that walked the earth...
就横行世界的英雄...的形象再生
Iong before the pale religions of civilization infected humanity's soul!
滚!
Go!
不要哭嚎了
Stopyour bawling,
你这软弱的人类垃圾
you weak little speck ofhuman trash.
好... 我走!
All right... I'll go!
- 你看看我是怎么走的  - 通电
- You justwatch me go!   - Hit it.
再来!
Hit it again!
不行 长官 没有能源了 有种反电磁场存在
We can't, sir. There's no power. Some kind of counter-electromagnetic field.
冲进去消灭目标 冲进去!
Move in andassault the target. Move in!
冲 冲!
Move, move, move!
长官 我在雷达上找到它们了 梨湖
Sir, I've located them on radar. Pear Lake.
呼叫部队
Call up the task force.
这就对了
Yes!
对了 继续打
That's right. Keep fighting.
你越打 我就能从你身上吸收的更多
The more you fight, the more of you I take.
奇怪 我们侦测到异乎寻常的降温
Strange. We're reading a phenomenal drop in temperatures there.
但同时又有强烈的辐射
But simultaneous radiological activity.
他们吸取了周围的能量
They're absorbing all the ambient energy.
睡吧...布鲁斯 永远忘记这一切
Sleep now, Bruce, and forget forever.
不要再反抗了...把你所有的能量都给我
Struggle no more... and give me all ofyour power.
你认为你受得了?拿去吧!
You think you can live with it? Take it!
都拿去吧!
Take it all!
哦 爽!爽!
Oh, yes! Yes!
收回去吧
Take it back!
不要停止!
It's not stopping!
收回去吧
Take it back!
先生们...攻击
Gentlemen... release.
伽马弹已发射
Gamma charge away.
作个甜蜜的梦吧!
Sweet dreams.
一年后
- 你好!  - 贝蒂 是你吗?
- Hello?   - Betty, is that you?
- 你好 爸爸?  - 我很高兴能找到你
- Hi, Dad.   - I'm glad I caught  you.
- 我也很高兴你能打来  - 谢谢
- I'm glad you called.   - Thanks.
贝蒂...你和我...
Look, Betty... you and I--
你和我都知道 布鲁斯不可能在那次爆炸下幸存下来
well, we both know that Bruce couldn't have survived that blast.
但是...你知道...
But... well, you know--
- 怎么了?  - 你知道
- What is it?   - Well, you know.
老样子 我总是有幻觉
The usual loonies. Seein' things.
只不过现在看到的全是绿的
Only now everything's green.
对
Right.
听着...
Look, uh...
万一他幸存下来...
ifby some chance he did survive...
他应该会联系你 尝试和你接触
and he should try to contact you, try to get in touch,
你会告诉我 对吗?
you'd tell me, wouldn'tyou?
不...我不会
No... I wouldn't.
但你我都知道 我不可能不这么做的
But you know as well as I do, I wouldn't have to.
我是说 我的电话被窃听 我的电脑被监控
I mean, my phones are bugged, my computer's tapped.
我处在监视之下
I'm under surveillance.
我告诉你
I'll tell  you, though,
如果他还活着
that ifhe were alive,
我不希望他来找我...
I'm the last person I would want him to come to...
因为...虽然我是如此想念他
because... as much as I miss him,
我...我...我爱他
I... I... Ioved him.
嗯...
I, um--
对
Yeah.
贝蒂 我很抱歉
I'm sorry, Betty.
我非常抱歉
I am so sorry.
我知道
I know you are.
听爸爸的话 按时吃药 好吗?
好
S'i.
拿走所有的药品
安静!
坐好
闭嘴
住在这里的人需要这些药品
你是什么东西?能决定这些人需要什么?
这些人在帮助我们的敌人
也许你也是
都拿走
这些是政府的财产
你很令我生气
你不会喜欢看见我生气的样子的